Runs a LiteRT-LM model interactively or with a single prompt.

  
  Examples:
    # Run interactively using a model ID from 'litert-lm list'
    litert-lm run my-model

    # Run with a single prompt using a local path
    litert-lm run ./model.litertlm --prompt "Hi there!"

    # Run directly from a HuggingFace repository
    litert-lm run --from-huggingface-repo org/repo model.litertlm

Usage: litert-lm run [OPTIONS]
                     MODEL_REFERENCE

Options:
  --prompt TEXT                   A single prompt to run once and exit.
  --preset FILE                   Path to a Python file containing tool
                                  functions and system instructions.
  --no-template                   Interact with the model directly without
                                  applying prompt templates. That means the
                                  input should include all control tokens for
                                  the model expected.
  --max-num-tokens INTEGER        Maximum number of tokens for the KV cache.
  --filter-channel-content-from-kv-cache
                                  Whether to filter channel content from the
                                  KV cache.
  --vision-backend [cpu|gpu|]     The backend to use for vision encoding.
  --audio-backend [cpu|gpu|]      The backend to use for audio encoding.
  --attachment FILE               Path to an attachment (image or audio only).
                                  Can be specified multiple times.
                                  Attachements are placed before the first
                                  user text prompt.
  --top-k INTEGER RANGE           The number of top logits used during
                                  sampling. If not set, use the default from
                                  the model or engine.  [x>=1]
  --top-p FLOAT RANGE             The cumulative probability threshold for
                                  nucleus sampling. If not set, use the
                                  default from the model or engine.
                                  [0.0<=x<=1.0]
  --temperature FLOAT RANGE       The temperature to use for sampling. If not
                                  set, use the default from the model or
                                  engine.  [x>=0.0]
  --seed INTEGER                  The seed to use for randomization. If not
                                  set, use the default from the model or
                                  engine.
  --backend [cpu|gpu]             The backend to use.  [default: cpu]
  --enable-speculative-decoding [auto|true|false]
                                  Speculative decoding mode ("auto", "true", "false").
                                    - auto: Automatically determine the speculative decoding behavior from the model metadata.
                                    - true: Force enable speculative decoding. It will throw an error if the model does not support it.
                                    - false: Force disable speculative decoding.  [default: auto]
  --verbose                       Whether to enable verbose logging.
  --from-huggingface-repo TEXT    The HuggingFace repository ID to download
                                  the model from, if set.
  --huggingface-token TEXT        The HuggingFace API token to use when
                                  downloading from a access gated HuggingFace
                                  repository. This can also be set via the
                                  HUGGING_FACE_HUB_TOKEN or HF_TOKEN
                                  environment variables, or by running `hf
                                  auth login`.
  -h, --help                      Show this message and exit.
